<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>infra on ian.ist</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/tags/infra/</link><description>Recent content in infra on ian.ist</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 13:34:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ianist.neocities.org/tags/infra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Migrated From K8s</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/why-i-migrated-from-k8s/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 13:34:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/why-i-migrated-from-k8s/</guid><description>At the time of this writing, my blog is still hosted with Vercel, however I think I will eventually move it to my VM. However, all the other sites and services I host have been migrated to my new VM (at the time of writing, only Nextcloud hasn&amp;rsquo;t been migrated, but it never made it into Kubernetes anyway). Why the switch? Well, I started using kubernetes after I took a job as a consultant doing SRE work.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up A Firewall</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/setting-up-a-firewall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:50:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/setting-up-a-firewall/</guid><description>Introduction I am migrating from Kubernetes to a VM. The tl;dr on the VM is that it&amp;rsquo;s an Ubuntu machine, serving my various sites and services with Caddy. The sites and services are all running in docker containers and the Caddy server proxies traffic to the specific containers. I am migrating from Kubernetes because it is expensive to run a cluster and it&amp;rsquo;s far more than I need. I had migrated to Kubernetes when I was doing consulting work as an SRE however, I am now very focused on being a developer, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t wish to lose my SRE skillset, I also cannot justify the cost, maintenance, or cognitive load required to keep that cluster up and working, thus a VM.</description></item><item><title>Vercel Woes</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/vercel-woes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/vercel-woes/</guid><description>Vercel is the company behind Nextjs and also a hosting platform that works with static site generates (Huga, Jekyll, Zola, etc.) and server side generators (Nextjs). I&amp;rsquo;ve been using them to host my new blog since it&amp;rsquo;s inception because they promise &amp;ndash; and mostly make good on the promise &amp;ndash; easy deployments. Well&amp;hellip; ian.ist is a little different because it&amp;rsquo;s two different repos. There is the Sylvan repo which contains the Nextjs code that parses org files and displays the content and there is my private org repo which holds the content.</description></item><item><title>Deployment. How Do?</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/deployment-how-do/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/deployment-how-do/</guid><description>Introduction Currently, ian.ist is hosted with Vercel. I am using Vercel and not my Bitranchlabs Infra because it was easier, and I am also not sure if I am going to keep my Kubernetes stuff running &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s $50+ / month for something I really don&amp;rsquo;t need. Vercel is great, I have no real reason to leave, except that my website&amp;rsquo;s content is in my private org repo, while the rest of the site is in the Sylvan repo, and the org content must be mounted into the Sylvan repo in order to build this site.</description></item></channel></rss>