<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>emacs on ian.ist</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/tags/emacs/</link><description>Recent content in emacs on ian.ist</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 05:56:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ianist.neocities.org/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Better Template Func</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/a-better-template-func/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 05:56:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/a-better-template-func/</guid><description>In a previous post I talked about a function I wrote that allowed me to stub out a few of the properties required for working with Sylvan. I have since updated that function a little. It&amp;rsquo;s still not ideal and I have one or two issues with it still, but I wanted to share the updated function nonetheless. As a sidenote, unless I outright delete this function for some reason, it shall always be visible in it&amp;rsquo;s most up to date from in my literate config.</description></item><item><title>Emacs From Scratch, Part 0</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/emacs-from-scratch-part-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 16:29:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/emacs-from-scratch-part-0/</guid><description>My experience with Emacs can be split into two parts:
Emacs with doom Realizing Doom didn&amp;rsquo;t load and quitting Emacs as quickly as possible and trying to figure out how to get back into Doom I have been experiencing some annoyances with emacs lately. It hangs or lags or chokes on large files (over 1000 lines) and it crashes sometimes. Partly out of a desire to strip back and get a leaner emacs, and partly out of a desire to really &amp;ldquo;try&amp;rdquo; emacs without the help of someone else&amp;rsquo;s config, I am going to attempt to build my own emacs from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Literate Dots Part 1 ZSH</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/literate-dots-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/literate-dots-part-1/</guid><description>I had mentioned tangling all the things yesterday, and I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and gotten a literate Zsh config up and running this morning. I&amp;rsquo;ve also created a new repo for it here.
Setup-wise, I went through a few different configurations to keep this DRY and eventually settled on setting global tangle settings in the properties drawer and then specifying each block&amp;rsquo;s output file in the source block. I might update this eventually, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t convince babel to run any other way.</description></item><item><title>My Dirty Hack to Template Files</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/my-dirt-hack-to-template-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/my-dirt-hack-to-template-files/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s actually kind of hard to use a template to create a new file. Apparently this is part of Doom, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to get teh file-templates to work in Doom. My dirty hack to get this working was to create a function that calls a new buffer, inserts some heading info into that new buffer, and then tells the buffer use the major mode of org-mode.</description></item><item><title>Tangle All The Things</title><link>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/tangle-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://ianist.neocities.org/blog/tangle-all-the-things/</guid><description>So I had this idea last night, and like with all great ideas I googled it see if anyone else had come up with it first. To my dismay, I was far from the first person to have this awesome idea. The idea? Literate dotfiles!
Imagine how great it&amp;rsquo;d be! You write a single file, let&amp;rsquo;s call it dotfiles.org and then inside of that you write all your dotfiles and document them.</description></item></channel></rss>